Be careful what you search for.
Life is a horror, science fiction, mystery film directed by Daniel Espinosa.
The six-member crew of the International Space Station is tasked with studying a sample from Mars that may be
the first proof of extra-terrestrial life, which proves more intelligent than ever expected.
Dr. David Jordan, played by Jake Gyllenhaal.
Rory Adams, played by Ryan Reynolds.
Miranda North, played by Rebecca Ferguson.
Sho Murakami, played by Hiroyuki Sanada.
Ekaterina Golovkina, played by Olga Dihovichnaya.
Hugh Derry, played by Ariyon Bakare.
Life is a 2017 American science fiction horror film directed by Daniel Espinosa, written by Rhett Reese and Paul Wernick and starring an
ensemble cast consisting of Jake Gyllenhaal, Rebecca Ferguson, Ryan Reynolds, Hiroyuki Sanada, Ariyon Bakare, and Olga Dihovichnaya.
In the film, a six-member crew of the International Space Station
uncovers the first evidence of extraterrestrial life on Mars.
When members of the crew conduct their research, the rapidly evolving life-form
proves to be far more intelligent and dangerous than expected.
The development of Life began in November 2015, when it was announced that
Espinosa would direct a film set in space written by Wernick and Reese.
After the deal with Paramount Pictures was not confirmed, Sony Pictures signed on to handle the
worldwide distribution rights and co-finance the film, with Skydance in March 2016.
The casting call took place in January 2016, and filming took place in
France, New York City and Vietnam between February and July.
The visual effects were handled by DNEG, Industrial Light & Magic,
NVIZIBLE, One of Us, Outpost VFX and Atomic Fiction.
It premiered at South by Southwest on March 18, 2017, and was theatrically released
in the United States by Sony Pictures Releasing on March 24, 2017.
It received positive reviews on Rotten Tomatoes and mixed reviews on Metacritic.
It grossed $100 million worldwide against a $58 million budget.
The film explores themes of planet mars, alien
life-form, space, astronaut, space station.
The tone is mind_bending and dark and thought_provoking.